[narrator, in English] Sedona, Arizona.
[Noel, in Japanese] It's
almost time to be with everyone again.
This may be
the first time we've been apart this long.
I wonder how they're doing?
It's the special
summer break Noel organized
for the Travis Japan members.
At the foot of the Rocky Mountains
where the desert winds blow
lies the real America
the members have yet to see.
The Travis Japan members
except for Noel divide up into two groups
and head to their final destination.
Sedona, Arizona.
Noel sets out to Sedona on his own
before the others
to quietly prepare
a warm welcome for them.
Travis Japan
SUMMER VACATION!! IN THE USA
[in Japanese] Team A is closing
in on Sedona, where Noel awaits.
With time to kill before the reunion,
they decide
to make a quick detour to a nearby town.
[in English] Flagstaff, Arizona.
[in Japanese] It's been a while
since we last saw a train.
Come to think of it, we've hardly seen
any railroad tracks this trip.
This is some kind of a station, right?
[Umi] This is the Flagstaff station…
[Chaka] I wonder
if travelers come here by trains.
-Good point.
-This is amazing.
You know what this reminds me of?
Stand By Me.
That's right,
they walk along the train tracks.
-[Shizu] I saw a train pass through.
-It's such a picturesque town.
-It should be featured in a movie.
-[Umi] This place has great ambience.
[Chaka] Do you think sleeper trains
pass through here?
-[Umi] I'd say.
-[Shizu] Not a bad guess.
Like… maybe you could get
around by trains?
-What an adventure that'd be.
-There might be a train culture like that.
-Well, shall we get going?
-[both] Let's go.
[Chaka] Umi…
you've leveled up.
By that,
you mean his fashion. Look at your neck.
I stumbled
upon so many wonderful accessories.
-Great style. I love it.
-See?
-This one's silver, and this here's gold.
-You're blinged-out.
I'm wearing five,
and that's just necklaces.
-No friggin' way.
-You've got so much bling.
-I'm decked out.
-But I like this one.
Check it out. It's reversible.
Whoa.
[Umi] I could go for some coffee. You?
-Let's sip coffee as we stroll.
-[Shizu] Let's grab coffee, then.
What a fancy place.
It's much larger than I expected.
Here's an idea.
Before we head to our next stop,
you want
to grab coffee and explore the town, yeah?
How about this?
We play rock, paper, scissors
-and the loser's on coffee duty.
-I'm in.
-The winners check the city out.
-We'll check it out.
-Ready?
-The loser covers the tab?
-Loser fetches coffee.
-The winner pays.
-Deal.
-We've gotta let the winner pay.
-Winner pays tabs Flagstaff roshambo?
-[exclaims]
Ready? Winner pays tabs Flagstaff,
rock, paper, scissors…
-Wait, wait…
-What the heck, that wasn't fair!
-I thought… I won…
-The timing was wrong.
That was cheating.
-Making excuses now, huh?
-What a sore winner.
-You won't fetch us coffee, then?
-Hold on, I'm not complaining.
-But are you sure about that round?
-Me? No, it didn't seem fair to me.
-Okay, then.
-Last chance, okay?
Here.
-Ready?
-Ready, go.
[all] The winner covers
the tab, rock, paper, scissors.
-Man, I wanted to play lackey.
-How the table turns.
-[Umi] Oh, shoot. You're a real man.
-Yep.
-This is what I get for suggesting it!
-[laughing]
You shot yourself in the foot with that.
-This is hard to watch.
-I'll man up.
-Just coffee, yeah?
-That's right.
-And only small servings.
-Yep, a short will do.
Wouldn't you rather have
a large if they have one?
-I prefer a bigger size, but…
-It'll be too bulky to carry around.
-You're right. It'll get in the way.
-Well, I'll leave it to you.
-I'll find somewhere to grab coffee.
-Where are you going?
-You can walk around.
-Okay.
Well, there we go.
That's everyone's coffee.
I'm the one who suggested it, but…
[in English] Excuse me.
[in Japanese] Man, this is pathetic.
Here I am,
everyone's drinks with both hands.
[in English] It is so beautiful.
-[in Japanese] How pretty. See?
-It's a work of art.
-Ain't it something?
-Right?
There's no way someone made this by hand.
-[Umi] Such craftsmanship.
-This is legit artwork.
[in English]
And then he does the Monument…
-Monument Valley.
-Monument Valley? Wow.
-Yeah, Monument Valley.
-We went to.
-Yes.
-[Umi, in Japanese] That's incredible.
Whoa.
-Hey, isn't it cute?
-Which one?
Wow.
Shoot. I've got a feeling
it's another fateful encounter.
Add that to the collection. [laughs]
-[Shizu, in English] Wow.
-[Umi] May I try this bangle?
[worker] Yeah.
Holy cow. Could you hold this
for me, Shizuya?
[Shizu] Of course.
[Umi, in English] Thank you.
[worker] So you go… Yeah.
-Exactly. Kind of on the outside.
-[Umi, in Japanese] This one's legit.
It's…
There we go.
[Shizu] I love the design.
-[worker, in English] That's beautiful.
-[Umi] Yeah, it's beautiful.
-[in Japanese] And the collection grows.
-Isn't it sick?
I can't believe I stumbled
upon such a beautiful gem.
I'm delighted.
-[Shizu] You look happy.
-Yep.
-My heart skipped a beat when I saw it.
-[chuckles]
Chaka… He's here alone. Huh?
-Thanks… Thank you very much!
-Thank you, thank you!
-Thank you very much.
-I feel terrible.
-Boss!
-Hey, Boss.
-Enjoy your drink.
-Seriously, sorry about the trouble.
Then I'll take one.
-Thanks.
-Thanks for going out of your way.
Time for a sip.
Do you want to explore the area?
-Huh? What? Hey… Sorry.
-Huh? What? What's the matter?
-Are you upset?
-Excuse me…
-Chaka…
-Let's go, Sensei.
…do you want to put your trash
in here? I'll take the cup holder.
-Thanks.
-Are you upset, Sensei?
-Wait, are you pouting?
-He's upset.
Not at all.
What gives me the right?
-Then at least act like you're not mad.
-It was my idea.
-Be pleasant.
-[Chaka, in Japanese] What a stylish city.
-[Umi] You're right.
[Chaka] This bus stop is cute too.
[Umi] It sure is.
Do you wanna sit for a minute?
[Shizu] I'm up for it.
-We could stage a magazine shoot here.
-How nice.
Right?
It's got a proper roof.
It's the best.
What a charming little bus stop.
[Umi] Where are we headed again?
Something "owl cafe," right?
-"Toasted," I think.
-I've been looking for it.
What does
the English word, "toasted", mean?
It could mean
"toast," as in toasted bread.
-It doesn't have special meaning?
-I guess "toast"
-must refer to toasting something.
-This place is packed.
-There it is.
-Right?
-[Shizu] They went crazy with the owls.
-"Toasted Owl."
[Umi] See? There are owls everywhere.
[Chaka] "Owl" must refer
to the bird, "owl."
-[Shizu] Let's check it out.
-Is it awake or asleep?
It's definitely awake.
It's more alert than the other ones.
Does it go, "hoot"?
You're right. Their eyes are bulging out.
Bloodshot, even.
-[Shizu] Let's enter.
-[Chaka] Well, here we are.
-[all, in English] Hi.
-[Chaka] Three of us.
-[server] Three?
-Yes.
-[Shizu] Hey.
-How are you?
[Umi] Thank you.
-What a hearty serving!
-Taco salad?
-Yeah.
-Isn't it awesome?
[chuckles]
-Oh, yeah. Thank you.
-And tacos for you as well.
And here's
your side of eggs, if you'd like.
-Oh, that'll be mine.
-Or that's you?
-Yeah.
-No, no, no. Okay. There you are.
-Thank you.
-Uh-huh. Enjoy.
-Thank you so much.
-Yeah.
-We have question…
-Okay?
…of why the name say "Toasted Owl."
-Toasted Owl?
-Yeah.
Um, I used to be a teacher,
and… during the Harry Potter days.
-Uh-huh.
-And so all the kids brought me owls
because I said I loved
the owl in Harry Potter.
And it got kind of weird.
I had too many owls.
And so I stopped teaching
and I decided to open a restaurant.
-[Umi] Whoa!
-Whoa.
And with all these owls
and then it just became huge.
So we have three,
and we're opening
a fourth one in about two months.
-So, it's been a lot of fun.
-[exclaiming]
That's inspired by Hedwig?
-Exactly. Uh-huh.
-Uh-huh.
-You know. Harry Potter is the bomb.
-[Umi] Yes.
Well, before you guys leave,
pick out a T-shirt.
It's on the house,
and you can wear the owl out…
-Home, and it's… I'm glad you're here.
-Ah.
Thank you very, very much.
[Chaka] That's souvenir, great souvenir.
It is a good souvenir.
You'll always think of the owl.
-[Umi] Yeah, you look cute.
-Ah, so cute.
You so talented.
-Oh, I don't… No, I'm just a…
-Yeah. [chuckles]
-I'm just really funny, can I like…
-[chuckling]
-Thank you so much.
-Thank you so much. Enjoy your meal.
-Yeah, appreciate it.
-Enjoy.
-[Umi, in Japanese] It looks decadent.
-[Shizu] Amazing.
This cafe owner drew
inspiration from a movie.
-In other words, a work of art.
-That's what made her want to open shop.
[Chaka] She opened
this cafe through sheer willpower,
and it's now
one of the most popular spots in town.
This is the kind
of town where dreams can come true.
This place is her canvas, so to speak.
[Shizu] Yes.
This town's got a real motley crew.
-Your tacos looks scrumptious.
-[Umi] Well, I mean,
-I've gotta eat tacos, you know?
-[Shizu] Mm-hmm.
-I crave it from time to time too.
-I feel you.
[Shizu] It's delicious.
Yum.
[Shizu] What a cute T-shirt.
-[Umi] Right?
-They even gifted us T-shirts.
-We had many encounters on this trip.
-Yeah, no. It was the best trip ever.
-Now, finally…
-Yes.
That's a wrap for our summer trip.
No joke.
-We were on the road for an entire week.
-Good work, guys.
We're about to regroup
with Team B and Noel, I'm guessing.
Then we'll travel together.
Team A's journey ends here.
Thanks for the ride, guys.
I appreciate you guys.
It was a good one.
-There.
-[grunts]
-Thanks for the adventure.
-Thank you for the good times.
Well then,
we'll join
the rest of the TJ members. Agreed?
[all] Agreed!
[clapping]
-[Shizu] Let's go!
-[Umi] They're clapping for us.
[in English] Thank you.
-Thank you.
-[Shime] Thank you.
[in Japanese] Phew, it's hot.
So hot.
-[Machu] Phew.
-Hot, hot.
So, what's on the agenda today?
Today, we are…
"You will take part
in a Native American celebration."
-What's that?
-A celebration?
-A celebration? Is that like, a festival?
-It's a festival!
Yes. "Your timing couldn't have been
any better. You're in luck."
-[laughing]
-Wow, that's a little…
-Well, shall we join the festivities?
-Shall we?
-I'm intrigued. Let's go check it out.
-Yep.
-Let's go. Talk about the sweltering heat.
-No joke.
Shall we get going?
-Machu, are you enjoying your ice cream?
-Hmm?
[muffled] Ice cream tastes
best on a hot summer day.
[chuckling]
-[Genta] Then, let's go!
-[Machu] Let's get going.
-[Genta] Tired of driving yet, Machu?
-It's going great. It's smooth sailing.
-Seriously? Thanks for taking the wheel.
-Yep.
-Thanks from me too.
-Don't mention it.
Are we almost there?
[laughs] Now, don't rush the driver.
[Genta] I wonder
what a Native American festival is like.
-[Shime] Yeah.
-[Machu] I can't imagine it at all.
[Genta] Neither can I.
It's way too hot.
[Machu] Hey, Shizuya.
-I wonder how they're doing.
-[Genta] Those guys, man.
-I miss everyone. Yeah.
-Me too.
I'm really starting to miss them.
-We really are like best friends, huh?
-I think so.
Wild that we can't wait to see them again.
Yeah.
-It felt a little empty without them.
-I know, right?
-I feel it too.
-Not that you two aren't any fun, but…
-Wait, are we not good enough for you?
-You don't think we're good enough?
[sighs]
-That's not what I said.
-Whoa, careful, careful.
-Keep your eyes on the road.
-Seriously though. Focus on the road.
-My bad, my bad.
-[laughing]
-That was lame.
-Yeah, you looked lame. Geez.
[Machu] Sorry to put your lives in danger.
[Shime] Wonder what Zuya-nii is doing.
[Genta] I bet he hasn't stopped
complaining the moment they took off.
I always lift the mood,
calling him "Zuya-nii" and all.
-But he doesn't have Genta and me around.
-Yep.
-[Genta] Right?
-It's true.
-I bet he's a Debbie Downer without us.
-Bet he's complaining nonstop.
This whole trip feels casual,
not like work.
-Yeah.
-My guess is Umi and Chaka
aren't as enthusiastic
as they usually are.
I'm really starting
to wonder how they're doing.
I'm scared for them.
I wonder if they're getting along?
What if Shizuya's mumbling
to himself the entire time?
-I wouldn't rule out that possibility.
-[Shime] Right?
[exclaims]
-[Shime] The horizon stretches endlessly.
-[Genta] What a view.
[Shime] The earth is red here.
-Hey, um…
-It's red.
How do I put it? Is the soil different?
What makes it so red?
It reminds me of the Grand Canyon.
Isn't Grand Canyon this shade of red?
[Shime] True,
it's all sorts of shades of red.
-[Machu] Amazing.
-[Genta] This view is very similar to it.
Look right, then left.
Right, then left.
The view is the same on both sides!
-Look to your right.
-Okay.
-Then look left.
-All right…
-Look right again.
-Yep.
Now, do it really fast.
-What happens then?
-Do it as fast as you can.
Okay.
-Did you get a bit dizzy?
-I sure did. I'm gonna get carsick.
Yeah.
-So don't do that.
-Thanks.
-[Machu, Genta laugh]
-What was that about?
[narrator, in English] Gallup, New Mexico.
[in Japanese] Gallup is a city situated
in the center of the Native American land.
Known as the heart of Indian Country,
numerous tribes such as the Navajo,
Zuni, Apache, and Hopi reside here.
Gallup is home
to the largest Native American
crafts and jewelry wholesale district
in the United States.
The trio head
straightaway to an Indian craft market.
How amazing. Whoa.
No way.
[Genta] This place is packed
with all sorts of things.
-It feels like a museum in here.
-I agree.
-This is remarkable… what?
-No way.
How cool.
[Shime] Cool indeed.
-What a collection.
-This is seriously cool.
Whoa, what a stylish belt.
-There are pieces of turquoise embedded.
-I see it. How cool.
-[in English] Do you wanna see it?
-Yeah, we wanna see.
-[in Japanese] Now that's rad.
-Don't you think it's stylish?
-[Genta, in English] Wow!
-[Machu] Wow!
Wow!
-[in Japanese] No way.
-[in English] So cool.
Very cool.
-[in Japanese] Oh, how cute.
-Isn't it awesome?
-I love it.
-What a great design.
-[Machu] It's your style, Genta.
-[Genta] I want to take it home.
-[in English] How much is it?
-[vendor] We can't.
[Machu] Yeah, yeah.
[vendor] So the judges come in tomorrow
and judge them,
and then they get
ribbons, or not, depending.
And then on Wednesday night,
it's first come first serve.
[in Japanese]
I'm taking note. Item number 387.
-You're locking in its number?
-Number 387.
-Are you gonna get it?
-How interesting.
-So, as I was browsing…
-[Shime] Yeah?
…I noticed the artist's age on the tags.
-Where?
-[in English] Age.
[vendor] So, this one is 13.
[Shime] Thirteen? [in Japanese] Thirteen?
[vendor, in English] This one is 13.
-[Machu] Thirteen. I liked this one too.
-[Shime] That's talent.
[Genta] This kid's 14. That's incredible.
See this one?
-Eight.
-[vendor] Seven.
-Seven?
-Five. Eight.
-[in Japanese] Seven years old!
-Eight, right? Eight here too.
-Wowza.
-Eight.
[narrator] On this day,
works by Native American children,
future artists in making, were on display.
-This one's by a nine year old.
-Basket weaver's just nine.
-[Machu] Nine?
-[vendor] Her parents…
-I love this.
-I love that we have a…
[Machu] You've got
carpet like this at home.
-I've got 'em all. Mmm.
-…a young girl weaving. It's great.
-She's just, uh, eleven.
-Oh.
-Eleven… Eleven?
-Eleven.
-Oh, eleven?
-Yeah.
-[Machu, in Japanese] They're so talented.
-[Genta] Look at them, hard at work.
-[Machu] They've made tons.
-[Shime] That's splendid.
[in English] They're at home
sitting with their grandma or their mom
learning how to weave.
Some… like, they're known for.
So, Navajos, we're silversmithers,
weavers, and then some pottery.
Uh, the plains tribes
up north, they did the beadwork,
um, and a lot
of the leather work. Sioux, Ojibwe.
Many kids are… can be Zuni and Navajo,
so they may learn both traditions because
they're learning from both families.
-Both.
-Oh.
And do their own thing.
-Wow. Genius.
-And you see that with the kids.
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
-They're… They're taking it
and doing it their own way.
Wow. Oh, my God.
So, it would be used
for tobacco and different things.
-And then the symbol.
-[in Japanese] Is this coral?
-[in English] Shark.
-Yeah. A shark, shark.
[vendor] This is also my daughter's.
She handmakes the paper flowers.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[vendor] That's our daughter's.
That's Mary Helen's as well.
-Whoa. Nice. Nice to meet you.
-Hello.
Oh!
-Nice meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
You… You made it?
-Yeah. All by myself.
-Really?
Really?
-[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa.
-[Genta] Impressive.
-[in English] You're genius.
-[child] Thanks.
[chuckling]
-[Machu] Look at this piece of work.
-[Genta] I love it. What a cool design.
-You made it?
-Uh-huh.
-Wow.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-So good.
-Thank you.
-[Machu] How old are you?
-Nine.
-[members] Nine?
-What's your name?
-Lance.
-Lance? Nice to… Nice to meet you.
-That's nice.
-Nice to meet you.
[in Japanese] You've got talent, kid.
-[in English] Amazing.
-Cool.
Very cool.
-Thank you.
-Yeah. Amazing.
-Awesome. You're so genius.
-Thank you so much.
-Thank you.
-[Genta] Have a good one. Thank you.
-[Shime] Have a good day.
-[Shime] Man, how admirable.
-[Genta] How cool.
-[Shime] Whoa.
-[Genta panting]
All the designs are just so cute.
-I love them all.
-[Machu] These are all designs you'd love.
My couch is full of cushions like these.
-[Shime] Your place is full of 'em.
-[Genta] Yeah, no joke.
I bet you'd like that one too, Genta.
-Don't you know it.
-Do you see that cushion?
[Genta] You know me.
I'm a sucker for cushions.
The cushions take
up my couch, there's no space to sit.
-[laughing]
-The Native American patterns
really match the couch.
I saw ones
like these when I went to your place.
-That's right.
-I thought you had one too many.
-They all look like these too.
-You're absolutely right.
There's no space to sit on my couch.
So I end up sitting on the floor.
[laughing]
-You're hilarious.
-That's not how a couch is used.
-It may not be wrong, but…
-But I love that.
-These would definitely match your couch.
-Right?
[in English] Very, very big.
I'm not gonna be able to open this
all the way out 'cause it's too heavy.
Too heavy.
-Cool.
-[vendor] Yeah, and it's folded.
Colors and the pattern came
from different areas.
So this is from…
This was originated in Ganado, Arizona.
-Arizona, yeah.
-That, that brown and stuff is Burnham,
-which is Burnham, New Mexico…
-Uh-huh.
So, um, there were
trading posts at those places.
And they would bring their rugs in
and the trading post owners would order
things that looked like this
for tourists and people to buy.
It's called Burnham Pictorial.
-Burnham is the pattern.
-Mm-hmm.
-And then Pictorial means the people.
-[Genta] Oh, nice.
-[vendor] So natural dyes.
-[Genta, Machu] Natural.
-[vendor] And there's some that might…
-Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
[in Japanese] I would've never known.
I thought these patterns were
random, you know?
-It's depicting people.
-My first time seeing ones like these.
[in English]
And all rugs are woven with a flaw.
-Flaw?
[vendor] A mistake. A purposeful mistake.
They're never made perfect
'cause no one is perfect.
So it's got a… No one's perfect so they…
When they weave,
they've got… You can't find it often.
Only the weaver can find it.
But it's got
a flaw because no one is perfect,
so they should
never create something that's perfect.
[in Japanese] The artist wove
in human flaw in their pieces.
I never knew such meaning was packed
in a rug.
-Meaning, huh.
-Right.
-Getting to hear it means the world to me.
-It's pretty big.
How fun it'd be to learn the meaning
behind them, then pick a pattern you like.
Or you can design
a room inspired by a specific tribe.
-I love that. What a cute idea.
-What a great idea.
Yeah. There are all kinds
of tribal cultures mixed up in my home.
-I totally understand.
-Who knew there was so much variety?
Sorry, I'm having too much fun in here.
-I'm enjoying it too.
-Glad to hear that.
-[in English] Thank you so much.
-Thank you.
[vendor] More than welcome.
[no audible dialogue]
[Noel, in Japanese]
Gallup is also cowboy country.
Cowboys, who are ranchers,
have become
a quintessential American icon.
They have inspired everything
from music to fashion.
There are two skills
every cowboy must know by heart:
horseback riding and lassoing.
Over time, the techniques used by cowboys
evolved into what is known as rodeo.
I want everyone to experience
what it's like to be a cowboy.
-[Genta] I see horses.
-I do too.
I can't believe this.
Whoa! Real horses. How cool!
I saw some in the truck too.
A horse in a truck? That's rad!
[in English] Hey. Ha.
[in Japanese] I see it too.
-[in English] Hi.
-Hi. Hello.
[person] Where are you guys from?
-Japan.
-Japan?
-Yeah.
-Are you ready for the rodeo?
-I never…
-The rodeo?
-Rodeo?
-Yeah.
-I've never been… see rodeo.
-Your first time?
-First time.
-Okay. It's gonna be right here.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-[attendant] Hello, hello.
-[Genta, Shime] Hello.
-[child babbling]
-[chuckling]
Yo, you gotta sign a waiver before you…
[Genta, in Japanese] What're you…
What're you doing?
[babbling]
[in English] Barrel racing.
-Barrel racing.
-Uh-huh.
Yeah, so you go around three barrels.
[in Japanese] Then, are you competing…
[in English] You're appear tonight…
Yeah. Yeah.
So I'll be out tonight on this side.
-Whoa.
-This way?
-She's an athlete!
-Oh.
-Yeah.
-Awesomesauce.
-You can just come and pet him.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-She's so cool.
You can come and… You can pet him, yeah.
[in Japanese] Oh, wow!
[in English] Wow!
Yeah. This is his tummy.
-[in Japanese] This is epic.
-How did it feel?
-Whoa.
-[Machu] It's velvety.
[Genta] This lady's legit.
[Machu] She's so cool.
No freaking way. Hello there.
His name… What's the name of the horse?
His… His name's Sky.
-Sky? Sky.
-Sky, yeah. Yeah.
-Cool.
-This is what they do.
-[members] Oh!
-[attendant chuckles]
[Machu] And you?
-[attendant 2] Yeah.
-Yeah.
-[Machu] Really?
-[Shime] Wow.
-[Genta] Oh, my gosh.
-[Machu] So, we can see tonight?
-[attendants] Yeah.
-[Machu] Really? Okay.
[attendant 2] Yeah, you'll see this too.
-[Machu, in Japanese] That's awesome.
-[Genta, in English] So fast.
[attendant] Yeah, they're pretty fast.
[Machu, in Japanese] How thrilling
it'll be to watch this in person.
-[Genta] That's wicked.
-[Shime] No kidding.
[in English] What's your name?
-[attendant] His name's River.
-River.
-Hey.
-Hey. Hey.
-Hey, River.
-[attendant] He rides horses too.
-[Machu] Really? [chuckles]
-Yeah.
[Shime, in Japanese] What a cute kid.
[attendant] He doesn't compete,
just rides 'em.
[Genta] Uh-huh.
[Machu] It's just riding.
-Yeah.
-[Machu] Sweet kid.
-[Genta] Cute.
-Hi. Hello.
[in Japanese]
Whoa, look at them. They're practicing.
-Amazing. Just amazing.
-How cool is that?
[Machu] Look at how he handles
the rope… Oh! [laughs]
[Shime] Nice work!
-[in English] Hi.
-Excuse me.
-Hi. Excuse me.
-Yeah.
-[Machu] What are you doing right now?
Uh, practicing with the dummy. So…
[speaks indistinctly]
[members] Ooh!
Is this difficult?
-Uh, little bit.
-[members] A little bit?
Yeah. You wanna try it?
-Oh, yeah.
-Really?
-Who wants to try their hands at it?
-Wow.
-[in Japanese] I wanna give it a shot.
-Go, go.
-Difficult?
-You wanna hold that.
-Okay.
Then when you sling,
you gotta bring it up here.
-Here?
-No, you wanna twist your wrists.
[in Japanese] Now that's tricky.
-Like this? It's hard!
-[Genta, Shime laugh]
[in English] Twist your wrists.
See how my wrist is moving like this?
-Okay.
-You wanna keep moving like that.
Right. [in Japanese]
Wait, it's tricker than I expected.
-Oh, man…
-[in English] Like this?
[in Japanese] Oh, wait! This is hard.
[in English] Now, when you hold your loop…
-Ah, ah, ah.
-…you're gonna start swinging like this.
[Machu] I'm getting a hang of it.
-Uh-huh.
-You're twisting your wrists.
-Like this?
-This?
-Like this? Samurai.
-Yeah.
-So when you swing it, you loop back here.
-Oh, yeah.
You swing and go like this.
When you're up here, it's flipping down.
So you're gonna keep going up and down.
-[Machu] Okay.
-[Genta] Uh-huh.
-[Machu] Huh? Ah!
-[laughs]
Very difficult, huh?
Like this?
-There you go. You can go to that dummy.
-Right.
-Walk over there.
-You can walk towards that dummy now.
Okay.
[laughing]
-Almost. Almost.
-Almost? Really?
-So difficult.
-[Genta] Whoa!
-[in Japanese] That's impressive.
-[Shime] Just wow. So cool!
Me next.
-[Machu] It's not easy.
-[Genta] I got it!
[in English] Thank you so much.
Yep.
-[in Japanese] Like this, and…
-[Machu] Go, go!
-No luck.
-[Machu cackles]
This is seriously tough.
But it's fun to try.
-[in English] Thank you.
-[wrangler] Yeah.
[in Japanese] Like this, and…
It's very tricky.
Crap!
[Machu chuckling]
[in English] Wow.
[Shime] So difficult.
It's pretty difficult, yeah.
But when you actually get the hang of it…
[Genta, in Japanese]
Oh, you throw it kinda to the side…
[Machu] Impressive.
-He nails his target every single time.
-Impossible.
-Seriously, I can't do it.
-[Machu] He doesn't miss once!
-Look, he'll do it again.
-[Genta] Yeah.
-Whoa!
-[Shime] Incredible.
[Machu, in English] Wow!
-Amazing.
-Amazing. Awesome.
[in Japanese] Even getting
the rope to spin is difficult.
-It really is.
-Right?
-[Machu] Oh!
-[Genta exclaims]
-[in English] Thank you for teaching us.
-[Shime, Genta] Thank you.
-[in Japanese] Thank you very much.
-Mm-hmm.
-[in English] Thank you. Wow.
-Yep. Have a good day.
-Thank you. You too.
-Yep.
Thank you so much.
[in Japanese] That was awesome.
-Let's practice it today.
-[Machu] Yeah, we need to practice.
[in English] Did you guys learn some?
-[Genta] Yeah. [laughs] Very difficult.
-[Machu] Yeah. So difficult.
Yeah. [laughs]
-Hi.
-This is Cobella.
-[members] Cobella.
-Yeah.
[members] Nice to meet you. Hello.
-You guys wanna ride a horse?
-Yeah.
-Yeah? Yeah?
-Okay.
-You guys wanna try holding it?
-Yeah.
[in Japanese] Is it heavy?
-Whoa, it weighs a ton.
-Yeah.
-[Genta] This thing…
-You guys wanna try it?
-Whoa, that's heavy.
-[chuckles]
Who knew it weighed so much?
-Ah, it's heavy… Oh, no!
-[laughing]
[in English] Yeah, it's heavy.
[Genta] Oh, yeah.
And then it tightens.
[members exclaiming]
-Just like that.
-[exclaiming]
And then this is the stirrup.
So when you get on,
your foot goes in here.
-[Machu] Okay.
-Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. Thank you so much.
[Shime laughs]
[Genta] Aren't you a cute little thing!
[Machu] Whoa, how cute!
-Well, if you're excited, you'll be happy.
-We're excited.
Yeah. So cute.
[Machu] Happy.
-You wanna get on?
-Yes.
-Whoa.
-Yeah, just like that.
Ah.
[Genta] Yeah.
Whoo.
-[wrangler] Ready?
-Ready.
-Yeah.
-[Genta] Yeah.
Okay. We can go
down the road, and then we can…
Let's go. Yeah, yeah!
-[in Japanese] It's the best.
-[Machu exclaims]
It feels great.
It's exhilarating.
Going horseback riding in the US is
the one thing I'll brag about.
Yeah.
I was considering getting
my driver's license.
-I'll opt for a horse instead.
-[Machu laughs]
This is pleasant.
[members] Howdy.
[Shime] Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
[Machu] Whoa!
[laughing]
-[Genta] How impressive.
-Don't they look cool?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
[Machu] How cool.
[Genta] I'm stoked to watch the rodeo.
-[Machu] Me too.
-[Shime] Right?
-[Genta] This is amazing.
-[Shime] Welp, I see the venue.
[Genta] Cowboys are everywhere!
[announcer speaking indistinctly]
[Shime] Whoa, here they come!
-[Machu laughs] Amazing. [exclaims]
-[Genta] Look. It's starting already!
[Shime exclaims]
We got VIP seating.
-This is nuts.
-Right?
[in English] When you see
the cowgirl coming out of the box,
-if they take one, two, three swings…
-Uh-huh.
…you gotta a chance.
-I see, I see.
-One, two, three.
-The longer you swing down there…
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-The best chance is if you have three.
-Three?
One, two, three, and then…
Mm-hmm.
Difficult.
-Whoa.
-[in Japanese] Here they come.
How cute. There's a little one too.
-[Genta] Holy moly! There she goes!
-[Shime] Yeah!
-Whoa.
-[Shime] Get 'em!
-[Genta] Oh, yeah.
[members exclaiming]
[Genta] How cool is that?
[Machu] Such speed!
-Whoo!
-[applause]
-Isn't this a great show?
-How impressive!
How do they nail the lasso every time?
No kidding.
-They're so skilled.
-What a show.
It was hard enough
with an immobile target.
It was a challenge.
-What an energized venue.
-The crowd went wild.
What a thrill.
It was such an exciting show.
What an experience.
Can you believe we rode horses? Actually?
-Man, I had the time of my life.
-Mmm.
Even better, we got to do it side by side.
-I know, right?
-I thought we were taking turns,
but we
all got to ride our horses simultaneously.
I know.
-Today was the best day ever.
-It felt so wonderful.
I heard that an even bigger
competition will be held soon.
Right.
There are many rodeo competitions,
and apparently,
the prize pool is pretty decent.
-That tracks.
-[Genta] I want to come again.
-We'll come here again.
-That's right.
-That was a blissful moment.
-Right?
Let's go say
goodbye to the cows before we leave.
-We'll say hi to the cows…
-No objection.
-…then we'll head out.
-[Genta] Let's go see the cows.
-Bye.
-[Genta] Good luck, you guys.
-See you again.
-Laters!
We'll be back.
-Bye bye.
-[in English] Love you guys.
-[in Japanese] Bye now.
-See you!
I'm hungry now.
Wanna go grab a bite somewhere?
-Good idea.
-Let's go find dinner.
-Or we'll go straight to bed.
-Wanna hit the hay?
We were on our feet all day.
-That's true.
-No joke.
[in Japanese]
Team B's trip also comes to a close.
Now, everyone's
en route to Sedona where Noel awaits.
Before they rejoin
the rest of the members,
Team B throw
one last hurrah for their ride.
-[Shime] Thank you.
-[Machu] No worries.
Thanks, bro.
-All righty! Let's get you cleaned up.
-[Machu] Hup.
-We'll make you spotless.
-Let's make it clean.
Ten minutes okay?
[Genta] Cool.
[Machu] Awesome!
It's my first time operating
a car wash. How does it work?
-I think you rinse the car with this.
-Oh!
Good going. Nice!
-Nicely done.
-[cheers]
[Machu] Thanks for taking us everywhere.
-Thanks, partner.
-Seriously, you were the best.
Scrub away!
This is cool.
Ready for more?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
-[laughing]
-Wait, wait, wait…
-Are you okay?
-I'm good, I'm good.
[shouts]
-You good?
-Shoot.
I'm covered in foam.
-Thanks, partner.
-[Machu] You're the best.
[Shime] Shall we give it a rinse?
Hold on.
Shime, can you bring the hose this way?
Okay, leave it to me.
-[Genta] Yes! Thanks, partner.
-[Shime] Hold on. The other way?
[Machu] Nice.
[Shime] Yes!
Let's move on to the bottom half, yeah?
[Shime] Let's go!
-This is kinda fun.
-[Machu, Genta] This is a blast!
-Hey, Shime, come here, and…
-Got it. Okay, thanks.
-[laughing]
-Careful, careful, careful!
Why'd you do that?
Hey, I told you! You'll get me soaked!
[machine whirring]
Well?
-Over there, over there.
-This way.
-[Machu] Go, go!
-[Genta] Get it!
[Machu] Time to dry the car.
-Whoa! We're gonna run out of time!
-[Genta] That's enough.
-Is it all done?
-[Genta, Machu] All done.
-It'll dry like this.
-Nice!
-It'll dry on its own.
-Thank you, thank you.
-Nice, nice, nice.
-Nice!
Man, that was a blast.
-It was so exciting.
-Right?
-Looks much better, doesn't it?
-Look how shiny it is now!
-The trip went by in a blink of an eye.
-Yep.
-I agree.
-True that.
[Machu] This week was packed
with unforgettable experiences.
-I completely agree.
-It was such an incredible week.
You'd never get to do this otherwise.
What moments stuck out to you?
Huh? I've gotta say, horseback riding.
[Machu] The horse, huh?
-You mean, yesterday.
-The horse… I love horses,
and I got to learn
about the Native American culture.
I was happy I got to connect
with the Native culture and people.
I love that for you.
-It really was the best.
-My highlight was the train.
The steam locomotive.
We liked the town too.
We did.
-[Machu] My favorite was the hot springs.
-[Genta] The hot springs.
It was sublime. I'm
a big fan of hot springs, as you all know.
-Right.
-And now, I can say
-I've been to the hot springs in the US.
-True.
Never did I think it was
in the cards for me.
It was an item checked off my bucket list.
-I can see that.
-[Genta] Yeah.
I wonder what Noel was trying
to tell us by pairing us up? Like what…
How do I put it?
What did he want us
to take away from this trip?
-Certainly, this was a trip of learning.
-I agree.
[Genta] We became
more aware of the American history
and the Native American story.
[Machu] I agree.
[Shime] This trip made us fall
even deeper in love with our passions.
-Definitely.
-[Genta] You're onto something. It's true.
We had countless encounters and growth.
[Genta] That's right.
We had many wonderful encounters.
[Shime] Everyone we met was wonderful.
-[Machu] They really were.
-Everyone we met was kindhearted.
-Nice, nice, nice!
-Good as new.
-Thanks, partner.
-Thanks!
Thank you, from the bottom of our hearts.
[Noel] Preparations are all set.
I can't wait to see everyone.
Translated by Megumi Hunter